<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>BLOG_NAME</title>
 <link href="YOUR_URL/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="YOUR_URL"/>
 <updated>2014-10-09T14:05:03-07:00</updated>
 <id>BLOG_URL</id>
 <author>
   <name>BLOG_NAME</name>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>heskey-and-liverpool</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/heskey-and-liverpool.html"/>
   <updated>2014-10-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/heskey-and-liverpool</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some classy football jokes told by a professional comedian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/IzlO7jFJ514&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>why is us womens soccer better than us mens respectively worldwide?</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/why-is-us-womens-soccer-better-than-us-mens-respectively-worldwide.html"/>
   <updated>2014-09-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/why-is-us-womens-soccer-better-than-us-mens-respectively-worldwide</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here are some reddit thoughts from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;why_is_us_womens_soccer_relatively_so_much_better&quot;&gt;http://www.reddit.com/r/soccer/comments/2huobg/why_is_us_womens_soccer_relatively_so_much_better/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>realtime coaching in soccer doesnt exist pt2</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/realtime-coaching-in-soccer-doesnt-exist-pt2.html"/>
   <updated>2014-09-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/realtime-coaching-in-soccer-doesnt-exist-pt2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If players, don&#39;t listen to their coach then what is the role of a coach? I like the term manager or boss that other countries seem to use to define this position. They are there to empower a player that must be responsive to what the game calls for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does miCoach help to enable that? &quot;Hey Quigsie, I see here that your total distance for the match was only 5.9 miles, as a Striker that&#39;s not good enough, I need you to work harder.&quot; Yelling this from the sideline would be utterly ridiculous. But, does communicating that after the match add value and empower the player?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quigsie takes this feedback and runs his face off the next game. His total mile count for this game was 8.2 miles. His coach is still unhappy, &quot;Coach, I did what you asked...&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue with data is and has always been making sense of the data we do have, rather than continuing to accumulate more and more data points. Quigsie famously quits after he loses the ball up top and every time that happens the opposing team is able to start their counter-attack much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My fear is miCoach data will help mask some of the intricacies of the game with its &quot;analysis&quot; and it will become a crutch of sorts for coaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Hey Quigsie, I need you to work hard to win the ball back after you lose it up top. Everytime you don&#39;t work hard to win it back it leaves the rest of the team out to dry.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen to what Klinsman said about this sentiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/o1TWEoSmRwU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>iron canary</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/iron-canary.html"/>
   <updated>2014-09-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/iron-canary</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h6&gt;change environments as quickly as possible&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canaries were once used as a rudimentary warning system for coal miners that went deep into mines where the air could potentially be hazardous. If you didn&#39;t hear the canary singing you knew the air was toxic and soon you&#39;d be in big trouble yourself. This crest is as a constant reminder to always be conscious of the footballing environment you put yourself in. As a player you won&#39;t last very long if you practice bad habits, give half efforts and aren&#39;t pushing yourself to be better every time you strap on your boots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surround yourself with players that are better than you, demand more from your teammates, focus on the important fundamentals, express yourself, play with joy, always be asking your coach what you can improve, watch a lot of professional games, play futsal, eat healthier, get extra fitness in, so that your footballing canary will be always singing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/fiftyfourfooty/iron-canary.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>realtime coaching in soccer doesnt exist pt1</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/realtime-coaching-in-soccer-doesnt-exist-pt1.html"/>
   <updated>2014-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/realtime-coaching-in-soccer-doesnt-exist-pt1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Adidas miCoach Soccer Elite Real-Time Smart System came out some time ago and was used at last year&#39;s MLS all-star game. Basically, players wear chips that measure time, avg speed, max speed, distance, high-intensity distance, and number of sprints. This is then streamed to the coaches, on the sideline in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, the thought of any one of the coaching staff looking down at an electronic device the whole game and then making &quot;real-time&quot; decisions based on these numbers is pretty sickening. But, this raises a bigger issue for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody ever really listens to their coach when they&#39;re on the field. You listen to the game. Sure, you have a general strategy communicated by the coach before the game, but part of the beauty in soccer is there aren&#39;t X&#39;s and O&#39;s for every imaginable scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game requires improvisation which requires creativity and that is something you can&#39;t hear from your coach on the sideline and certainly something you can&#39;t gather from a data sheet. At least not from the data sheet miCoach provides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;...to be continued with part 2 in a future post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>train with your shinguards</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/train-with-your-shinguards.html"/>
   <updated>2014-08-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/train-with-your-shinguards</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h5&gt;Train with your shinguards&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was in college we had this Police Officer that would come to the gym the same time as us for weight training. Officer Packer was the real deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time we saw Packer doing squats, hang cleans, military press or even juimping on the box he was in full gear. That means boots, badge, gun, pants, flashlight, the whole lot. We knew him well so we knew why he did it, but whenever somebody asked him why he was in full gear, the response was always the same-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;When I&#39;m out on the job I won&#39;t be in basketball shorts and a tank top, I&#39;ll be in full uniform. So, it makes sense to train that way.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&#39;re training keep everything as close to game day as possible. Whether it&#39;s wearing shinguards, LOUD communication, listening to your ipod when putting on your boots, a focused warm-up or your pre-game handshake with your boy. &#39;Train with your shinguards&#39; isn&#39;t just a literal translation, it&#39;s your state of mind.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>dont go out and shoot with a bag of balls</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/dont-go-out-and-shoot-with-a-bag-of-balls.html"/>
   <updated>2014-08-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/dont-go-out-and-shoot-with-a-bag-of-balls</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h5&gt;How many times..&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&#39;re looking to get extra work in do you take a bag of balls out and go shoot for an hour? You shouldn&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even as a striker, on a great day, you take probably 7-8 shots at goal. There are a number of other things you do far more often in a game that you can and should be working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://gfycat.com/ifr/RelievedAmbitiousGuppy&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; style=&quot;-webkit-backface-visibility: hidden;-webkit-transform: scale(1);&quot; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


&lt;p&gt;How many first touches do you take? How many 1v1 situations do you get in? How many passes do you make? How many tackles? How often do you call for the ball? How many runs should you be making? How many turns?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of other things you do more often in a game that you should work on perfecting. Things that happen over and over again in a 90 min match. And when you get good enough at those other things a goal is nothing more than a pass into the back of the net anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>parents dont care about winning pt2</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/parents-dont-care-about-winning-pt2.html"/>
   <updated>2014-08-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/parents-dont-care-about-winning-pt2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h6&gt;continued from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://54footy.com/blog/parents-dont-care-about-winning-pt1.html&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why does all of this go out the window in the form of unacceptable sideline behavior, team jumping, and questioning of coaching methodology. Oh and of course there are the endless emails, phone calls, and conversations about their kid, and sometimes, even other kids on the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not from a lack of understanding of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents naturally want the best for their kids, and for many parents this means getting their kids into a good college. American youth soccer is a HUGE investment of TIME and MONEY for parents and players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents fear if they don’t win, the team won’t get into the best tournaments, and if they don’t get into the best tournaments then they can’t be seen by college coaches and alas their ROI is not realized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents don’t care about winning they care about putting their kid in the best position to be successful in life. In reality club soccer can greatly facilitate this in 2 ways-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A player can get a scholarship to a university that the family couldn’t otherwise afford.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A player can get accepted to a university that would otherwise be difficult to get into without the added attention incoming collegiate athletes receive during the admission process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;That’s a lot of pressure to put on a club soccer coach and why sometimes you feel the brunt end of a frustrated, overbearing parent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;Simply put:&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your team went 0-15 and went to 0 major tournaments, but every single player went on to play at their dream school and developed immensely as soccer players during the season, would parents care half as much about winning? Doubtful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents don&#39;t actually care about winning.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>my old roommate does yoga</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/my-old-roommate-does-yoga.html"/>
   <updated>2014-07-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/my-old-roommate-does-yoga</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h5&gt;My old roommate was on her way to her hot yoga class.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I said, &quot;I can&#39;t do hot yoga, It&#39;s too slow for me.&quot; She immediately started attacking soccer, &quot;Oh, I&#39;d much rather be running up and down a field chasing a silly ball!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple things here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know the drill if you&#39;re a soccer fan living in America and having a discussion with somebody that doesn&#39;t quite get it. I went into the &quot;World&#39;s most popular sport..&quot; and &quot;yes, goals are only worth 1 point is why it&#39;s considered &#39;low&#39; scoring&quot; routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But also, with that logic anything can be reduced to this sort of non essential fun sucking paraphrasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;hot yoga&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;...oh, I&#39;d much rather sit in a flatulent filled room with a bunch of sweaty strangers..&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;riding rollercoasters&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;...oh, I&#39;d much rather get whiplash while some little kid potentially vomits all over my lap..&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;curing cancer&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;...oh, I&#39;d much rather stare in a tiny microscope all day being exposed to dangerous oncogenes..&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t particularly like playing football or baseball, but I can certainly appreciate the mental chessmatch between a pitcher and batter, top six, with 2 outs and a runner on 3rd. Or, the beauty in execution needed to drive the football 80 yds downfield with 4 min left in the fourth quarter. And yes, even the meditative introspection yoga demands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She got me thinking how I would describe soccer if it wasn&#39;t just running up and down a field chasing a ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, (when it&#39;s played the right way) it really is poetry in motion. It&#39;s all the instruments in a symphony playing to the same tune. It&#39;s a blank canvas for each artist to express their individual creativity. Every game is a chance to author a new novel and no two stories are ever the same. It&#39;s an escape where literally, nothing else matters.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>first to practice last to leave is bad</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/first-to-practice-last-to-leave-is-bad.html"/>
   <updated>2014-07-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/first-to-practice-last-to-leave-is-bad</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h5&gt;More specifically, it&#39;s only good, and not great.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, you&#39;re striving for great. This mindset is good but only for awhile because at its core it&#39;s selfish. When you&#39;re a part of a team a selfish mindset keeps you at good and never elevates to greatness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First to practice, last to leave undoubtedly improves you the individual but when you think about becoming a leader and achieving certain things only a &lt;strong&gt;team&lt;/strong&gt; can achieve it&#39;s not enough. You need to elevate those around you and get the best out of your teammates and this mindset doesn&#39;t support that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shifting your focus and efforts this way is a path to greatness because The Team will always have the potential to achieve more than the Individual.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Parents dont care about winning pt1</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/parents-dont-care-about-winning-pt1.html"/>
   <updated>2014-07-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/parents-dont-care-about-winning-pt1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h5&gt;No matter how much parent&#39;s soccer education improves, they&#39;ll never be completely satisfied.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something we hear often in the states is that soccer (yes soccer) is not a well understood sport in this country. Especially, by a majority of youth soccer parents. We’re champions of the world’s most popular sport in a country that barely flinches when they see a 45 yard Messi-esque run and can’t fathom how a 0-0 match can still be entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past World Cup in Brazil helped, but it was pretty clear that many Americans around the country were simply excited to cheer for something American and not necesarrily because of their love of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;But if parents only understood soccer better, THEN they would understand my coaching decisions and always support them!&quot; Sadly, this isn’t the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t believe me, consider parents of youth basketball players. A well understood sport this country is undoubtedly fanatical over. Do you think these parents are acting any different than soccer parents because they are well educated on the game?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They aren’t. They’re just...well...parents. Something changes when your kid is involved. Most all rational thinking goes out the window when you see your first born not playing in the “right” position or your youngest daughter getting specific instruction you don&#39;t agree with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents want to see their kid’s team win and when they don’t the coach is always the first to blame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;The good news&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parent don’t actually care about winning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you surveyed your player’s parents at the beginning of the season and asked what the number one most important part of their child’s youth sports playing experience was, how many do you think would list ‘winning games’ as their answer? Probably not very many. You’re more likely to get answers like skill development, sportsmanship, commitment, work ethic, fun, integrity, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;...to be continued with part 2 in a future post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>